https://www.rbauction.com/privacy-statement

Bidder Number: Maximum limit: Available limit: Activate online bidding Increase your bidding limit Activate online bidding Increase your bidding limit Bidding limit: Edit your profile Select an account to bid with
See today My Purchases Welcome Back!
As a reminder, we updated our Terms of Service on March 19, 2020 to clarify what you can expect from Ritchie Bros. when you use our services and what we require from you. Your continued use of your account means that you agree to these updates. {0} account terms and conditions privacy statement
We have encountered a server error. Please try again. Continue Cancel Sign-in Back
Home Legal PoliciesPrivacy Statement
Privacy Statement
Effective as of February 27, 2020.
Scope of and updates to this Privacy Statement
Who to contact with questions or for more information
What personal information we collect and process
Core asset disposition services
Other asset disposition-related services
Purposes and legal basis for handling your information
What we process information for
Data sharing with OEMs and their dealers
Other information regarding privacy
Responsibilities for receipt of information through services
Providing us with third party personal information
Children's privacy
Logging in to IronPlanet's online marketplaces using your Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers web account
Logging in to a preferred provider's site using Ritchie Bros. credentials
Links and Social Media Presences
Regional disclosures
1. Scope of and updates to this Privacy Statement
Being the trusted choice for your global asset management and disposition needs starts with Ritchie Bros.' unrivaled commitment to customer service.  As part of that commitment, we respect the privacy of our customers and users.  Whether we are helping to appraise, sell, inspect, buy, refurbish, transport or finance your heavy equipment, trucks, and other assets around the world, we are guided by our desire to meet your needs in a convenient, fair and transparent manner – and that includes making sure you understand how we handle personal information and what corresponding rights are available to you.
Ritchie Bros. is a global organization with companies located around the world that operate our multi-channel solutions for buying and selling, as well as our related service offerings. Our brand solutions include:
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Marketplace-E
GovPlanet
TruckPlanet
Kruse Energy
Mascus
SalvageSale
Leake Auction Company
Ritchie Bros. Financial Services
Ritchie Bros. Asset Solutions
Ritchie Bros. Inspection Services
Ritchie Bros. Appraisal Services
Ritchie Bros. Source
This Privacy Statement applies to ritchiebros.com and other Ritchie Bros. websites, services and solutions that collect information and display or link to this Statement, and that are owned and operated by a member of the Ritchie Bros. group of companies.  This Privacy Statement does not apply if the Ritchie Bros. website, service or solution does not display or link to it or where the website, service or solution makes its own privacy notice available.  This Privacy Statement applies equally to our digital handling of your information as it does to our offline collection and handling.
To understand which Ritchie Bros. company is responsible for the collection and further processing of your personal information, see the section below entitled "Data Controllers".
We may change this Privacy Statement at any time by posting the revised statement on this website and indicating the effective date of the revised statement.  The revised Privacy Statement will be effective once posted unless we state otherwise.
We may also supplement or modify our privacy commitments in this Privacy Statement through other notices we make available to you or through contractual commitments we enter in writing.
Where we've provided a translation of the English language version of this Privacy Statement, such translation is provided for your convenience only.  To the extent there is any inconsistency between the English language version and such translation, the English language version takes precedence.
2. Who to contact with questions or for more information
If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Statement or our practices, you can reach our Data Protection Officer through our Data Privacy Office at:
Ritchie Bros. Data Privacy Office c/o Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers Incorporated 9500 Glenlyon Parkway Burnaby, British Columbia, Canada V5J 0C6
Or use our privacy contact form.
3. What personal information we collect and process
Our multiple solutions are designed to help your business Move, Build and Grow.
Most of the information we collect, and process, is equipment related information and business contact information relating to, and provided by, our customers' employees or other workers.  In general, information is collected when a customer engages one of our brand solutions to provide services by entering a contract, creating an online account, coming into one of our auction locations to register for an auction, providing us information through a webform, or otherwise interacting with us.  Information may also be obtained from other sources.  For instance, brand solutions may share information, or an outside service provider is used to verify or supplement what we've received.  In some cases, the information we obtain is generated automatically when users engage with our digital services, such as browsing our websites, using our mobile applications, opening our communications or clicking on our advertisements.
While our solutions are generally not targeted at individuals buying or selling for personal, family or household purposes, individuals do engage with certain of our solutions from time to time for these purposes.
Some information we obtain from you may be more sensitive in nature and depends on the services you are engaging us to perform.  For instance, we may require ID numbers from a driver's license or other identity documentation to process transactions or facilitate the extension of financing to your business. Some of this information may be considered more sensitive in nature.
Certain of our brand solutions obtain and store personal information for the benefit of our corporate or government customers to provide those customers specific technology services.  In those circumstances, we are acting as a service provider and collect and process that information in accordance with our customers written instructions and our contractual arrangement.
Offering you the choice of multiple solutions for different needs means that each solution operates somewhat differently.  To learn more about the categories of information handled by specific solutions and their sources, read on.
3.1 Core asset disposition services
Our core asset disposition services include:
Brand
Details of Offering
Offers unreserved public auctions with onsite and online bidding, as well as other non-auction-related services (e.g. RB Logistics, private treaty, appraisal, inspections)
Offers an online only marketplace with featured weekly online unreserved auctions
Provides access to the MarketPlace-E online platform
Powers sector-specific solutions GovPlanet, TruckPlanet and Salvage Sale and provides the online auction platform to support online bidding at Kruse Energy and Leake Auction sales events Since you are required to have an IronPlanet account to use these specific solutions or to bid online, the categories of personal information collected, and sources, are the same
Operates an online public listing marketplace available on the web or through a mobile app where buyers and sellers can post ads and communicate with each other about equipment advertised
Offers auction and private treaty services tailored to the energy industry Online bidding is powered by IronPlanet's online action platform and requires an IronPlanet account
Offers auction services to the collector car industry Online bidding is powered by IronPlanet's online action platform and requires an IronPlanet account
The list below describes examples of the collection and processing of personal information by category and source for the core asset disposition services. Check marks indicate the relevant brand practices.
Note that since online bidding and private treaty sales for Kruse Energy and Leake Auction are facilitated through, and managed and supported by, IronPlanet's online auction platform, bidders and sellers (in the case of private treaty) must first create an IronPlanet account.  Accordingly, the information collected automatically (including through cookies or other similar tools) as identified under "IronPlanet" in the list below applies equally for Kruse and Leake online bidders and buyers.
Category: Account Registration Data
Description:
Data that identifies you – name, title, employment status, addresses, telephone numbers, email addresses, account password and in some cases, personal ID document numbers (driver's license, passport, national or state identity card, or SSN), age, nationality, tax identification numbers, and your signature
Sources:
Personal information you provide when buying or selling at an auction or by private sale, purchasing value-added services (appraisals, inspections, shipping, logistics, or repair & refurbishment), creating or updating an account or otherwise interacting with us
Information from your business colleagues or partners who add you to their online account
Personal Information contained on motor vehicle titles and other equipment registration documents we handle in a transaction
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Sources:
Personal information you provide when posting an ad on the marketplace, inquiring about a seller's item, registering for an account or otherwise interacting with us
Information from your organization who posts equipment ads on the marketplace
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Source:
Information from third-party business data providers or publicly available sources to supplement our sales leads and prospects
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Description:
Data needed to complete a check of the US Federal System for Award Management and an End User Certificate facilitating the transfer of an asset to a party outside the US Department of Defense – name, social security number or other personal ID number, date of birth, place of birth, telephone number, address, purpose of buying, signature and if applicable, their role as officer, partner or agent with the purchaser
Source:
Information US individuals provide when registering an account to bid and when buying certain GovPlanet equipment
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Description:
Social security number along with other identifying information on tax exemption forms
Source:
Personal information you provide when relying on a tax exemption for purchases of a sole proprietorship
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: Transaction Data
Description:
Data regarding self-listings, bids, purchases, or sales in a transaction
Sources:
Personal information you provide when listing, buying or selling at an auction or by private sale, purchasing value-added services or otherwise interacting with us
Information collected automatically when you use our websites, mobile apps and webservices to bid or buy
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Source:
Information from other solutions operated by members of the Ritchie Bros. group of companies
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Description:
Data regarding your online purchase of tickets to our auction events
Source:
Information from our third-party service providers managing the sale of tickets to our events and processing ticket payments
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: Payment Data
Description:
Banking information (account numbers and payment details) and credit card information necessary to process a bidding deposit or transaction
Source:
Personal information you provide when listing, buying or selling at an auction or by private sale, purchasing value-added services, creating or updating an account or otherwise interacting with us
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Description:
Payment information (account numbers and payment details) and credit card information necessary to process ad placements or other services
Source:
Personal information you provide when posting an ad on the marketplace or entering into a listing contract
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: Shipping and Logistics Data
Description:
Shipping, billing, and other information you provide in connection with the purchase or shipping of an asset, as well as information required for bills of lading or customs clearance (such as tax identification numbers or other identification numbers)
Source:
Personal information you provide when listing, buying or selling at an auction or by private sale, purchasing value-added services or otherwise interacting with us
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: Industry Preference, Interest and Feedback Data
Description:
Data regarding industry and equipment interests and preferences or assets you wish to value or sell when you complete a webform, engage with us on social media or at tradeshows, or participate in surveys, feedback forms, our online community discussion platform, contests and focus groups
Source:
Personal information you provide when interacting with us
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: Customer Service Data
Description:
Information relating to inquiries about services, dispute resolution, and, where applicable, recorded customer service calls
Source:
Personal information you provide when interacting with us
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: Visitor and Incident Log Data
Description:
Log data collected in connection with your entering our physical offices or auction sites, or in the event of an incident (motor vehicle collision, injury or environmental event) you are involved in or witness while onsite
Source:
Personal information you provide when visiting our offices or auction sites
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
GovPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: CCTV Data
Description:
CCTV video footage at our physical offices and sites
Source:
Personal Information collected automatically when you visit our physical offices and sites
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
GovPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: Online Account Usage Data
Description:
Data generated through actions you take which are linked to an online account, for instance when you create watchlists or saved searches, search inventory or results, change your communication and marketing preferences, register to bid or enter a Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers' auction ring online, whether you bid or not (including assigned bidder numbers, bid amounts, winning bids), or register for bidding privileges on an IronPlanet marketplace
Source:
Information collected automatically when you browse or login to our website, use our mobile apps and webservice
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Source:
Information collected by our online auction bidding engine service provider on our behalf
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: Geolocation Data
Description:
Geolocation data, including that of your mobile device when you enable the use of location services in your device settings or in app
Source:
Information from your device collected automatically when you browse or login to our website, use our mobile apps and webservices using cookies, web beacons and similar tools
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: Device Connection Data
Description:
Computer and other device connection data, such as page view statistics, data traffic to and from websites, referral URL, your IP address, access times, browser, language settings and web server log information
Source:
Information from your device we collect automatically when you browse or login to our website, use our mobile apps and webservices, and in some cases, using cookies, web beacons and similar tools
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Description:
Model or device type, operating system and version, browser type and settings, device ID or individual device identifier, advertisement ID, cookie ID, or IP address from which the device accessed our services
Source:
Information from your device collected automatically when you browse or login to our website, use our mobile apps and webservices using cookies, web beacons and similar tools
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Source:
Information collected by our electronic signature solution service provider on our behalf when interacting with contractual and related documents we send to you
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Category: Online Activity Data
Description:
Webpages of ours you visit, time of access, frequency and duration of visits, the links you click or other actions you take as part of your use of the website or mobile app
Source:
Information collected automatically when you browse or login to our website, use our mobile apps and webservices using cookies, web beacons and similar tools
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Description:
Information about your activities and interactions with sponsored or featured digital advertising content or our marketing emails, such as advertisements you were shown, when and where they were shown, and whether you clicked and took any subsequent action like filling out a webform or telephoning a seller on Mascus about their equipment
Source:
Information from our advertising and analytical service providers collected automatically when you browse or login to our website, use our mobile apps and webservices using cookies, web beacons and similar tools
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Source:
Information collected by our phone call analytics service provider on our behalf when you call us at a phone number (displayed for instance on our marketing landing pages or webforms)
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
Source:
Information collected by our phone call analytics service provider on our behalf when you call a seller at the phone number displayed on the ad listing page
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
IronPlanet
Mascus
KruseEnergy
Leake
For further information about the collection of data using cookies, web beacons and similar tools when you interact with our digital services, such as website or email communications, interact with advertisements or initiate certain telephone calls, check out "Cookies & similar technologies and your preferences" below.
We combine or link the personal information we collect from you with information we receive from the other sources identified in the chart above. Where we receive data from third parties, we try to confirm the information was lawfully collected and disclosed to us.
IronPlanet's other technology solutions – Marketplace Direct, Super Marketplace Direct, and GovPlanet Direct –power the direct marketplaces of some of our corporate and government customers.  To participate in their online sales events, you must have an IronPlanet account.  We do not handle the exchange of funds or otherwise participate in the closing of any transactions between you and our direct marketplace customers.  Information regarding your bidding activity – user name, location, bids placed – as a user of their direct marketplace is collected and made available to our customers for use and handling in accordance with their respective privacy policies.  As a service provider, we do not use this information for our own commercial purposes other than to perform the services of hosting and managing the functionality of the marketplaces for our customers.  If you have concerns about the use and handling of your information by these customers, you will need to contact them directly.
Mascus also provides tools for professionals to help manage their inventory, understand the used equipment market, publish listings on the Mascus online listing marketplace and reach bigger buying audiences.  Mascus' tools for professionals are part of the suite of tools offered under the Ritchie Bros. Asset Solutions brand.  Mascus systems power these tools for our professional customers.  For more information about the handling of personal information when interacting with these tools, refer to the Ritchie Bros. Asset Solutions section below.
3.2 Other asset disposition-related services
Our other asset disposition-related services include:
Ritchie Bros. Asset Solutions (RBAS) is a collection of tools – cloud-based inventory management system (IMS), managed and hosted custom webshops, mobile apps for inspection and inventory management, marketing tools and a data insights module – that we make available to our OEM, corporate and government customers on a subscription basis.  The tools are configured for use by our customers' end users – both for their employees and other personnel and for interested buyers of their equipment.
If you are an RBAS customer, your end users need to understand how you (and we) collect and process their personal information.  Accordingly, if you use a custom webshop or mobile app, you agree to post an up-to-date and accurate privacy notice on those tools that complies with the laws applicable to your business.  You also agree to obtain consent from your end users for the use and access of their personal information by us and other third parties.
Except as noted below, information about end users interacting with RBAS tools is collected and processed by us as a processor on behalf of our customer in which case we act on the instructions of, or as permitted by, our customer or their authorized internal end users.  We don't use the personal information we maintain about your end users who interact with your custom webshop to independently contact or market to them.  If you are an end user and have questions or concerns regarding the handling of your information, refer to the privacy policies made available by our customer (who may be your employer) through the relevant RBAS tool.
If you are a representative of our corporate or government customer subscribing for services, we collect your business contact information to establish and maintain our relationship with our customer as their service provider (e.g. customer service and invoicing).
We also collect IMS end user credentials and interactions with the IMS to monitor, log, analyze and test the security of the systems, networks, databases and applications supporting the IMS and to ensure compliance by the customer with our contractual arrangements.  We also use this interaction data to monitor and improve the general performance and usability of the IMS such as enhanced features, GUI layouts, and page responsiveness.
Information and data collected by us through management of RBAS tools will be used as necessary to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations.
Ritchie Bros. Financial Services facilitates financing and leasing solutions for auction customers and other equipment owners and dealers referred through our partner networks.  We do not offer financial products for personal, family or household purposes.  Personal information collected includes:
Category of Information
Description
Source(s)
Application and Identity Data
Data that identifies you as the principal or guarantor of a business applicant – name, residential address, birthdate, gender, social insurance or security number, phone numbers, email, ownership type and interest in the applicant, shareholder or member registers
Personal information you provide when applying for financial or insurance products, inquiring about a credit approval or rejection, or otherwise interacting with our account managers Information from third-party business data providers and publicly available sources to supplement leads and prospects
Application and Identity Data
Identification documentation including driver's licenses, passports or other government ID (e.g. social insurance or security number card)
Personal information you provide when applying for financial or insurance products or otherwise interacting with our account managers
Credit and Financial Data
Current and historical financial information, including tax returns, assessment notices, void cheques, estimates of net worth and financial statements
Personal information you provide when applying for financial or insurance products or otherwise interacting with our account managers
Credit and Financial Data
Credit bureau reports and other credit information
Information from credit reporting agencies and or credit grantors
Loan Approval Data
Data regarding a credit approval (e.g. the amount to be financed by a lender partner) and other data associated with completion of a loan transaction with a lender partner (e.g. financing documents)
Information you provide when executing a financing transaction Information received from a lender partner during the execution process
Industry Preference, Interest and Feedback Data
Data regarding industry and equipment interests and preferences, assets you wish to purchase, your business structure and financing or leasing needs
Information you provide when applying for financial or insurance products or otherwise interacting with our account managers
Online Account Usage Data
User data (e.g. account information, actions taken) relating to a user who creates a watchlist on the Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers or IronPlanet website
Information from other solutions operated by members of the Ritchie Bros. group of companies
Auction Lead Data
Successful buyer and runner-up bidder data (e.g. name, contact information, equipment bid on and purchased, price) for auction buyers and bidders from other solutions operated by members the Ritchie Bros. group of companies
Information from other solutions operated by members of the Ritchie Bros. group of companies
Referred Lead Data
Financing lead contact information and industry related information
Information from third party lead referral partners (for example, publishers who advertise and promote our services
Online Activity Data
Webpages and webforms viewed or submitted, time of landing, frequency and duration of viewing, the links you click or other actions you take as part of your use of the website or interaction with our email
Information from your device collected automatically when you browse the IronPlanet or Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers websites or fill out a webform using cookies, web beacons and similar tools
Online Activity Data
Information about your activities and interactions with sponsored or featured digital advertising content or our marketing emails, such as advertisements you were shown, when and where they were shown, and whether you clicked and took any subsequent action like filling out a webform or adding equipment to a watchlist
Information from our advertising and analytical service providers collected automatically when you browse equipment or login to the IronPlanet or Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers websites or interact with our emails using cookies, web beacons and similar tools
Device Connection Data
Model or device type, operating system and version, browser type and settings, device ID or individual device identifier, advertisement ID, cookie ID, and IP address from which the device accessed our services
Information from your device collected automatically when you browse or login to the IronPlanet or Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers websites using cookies, web beacons and similar tools
For further information about the collection of data using cookies, web beacons and similar tools when you interact with the Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers or IronPlanet website, our custom webforms or our email communications, check out "Cookies & similar technologies and your preferences" below.
We combine or link the personal information we collect from you with information we receive from the other sources identified in the chart above. Where we receive data from third parties, we try to confirm the information was lawfully collected and disclosed to us.
4. Purposes and legal basis for handling your information
We use your personal information for a range of different business and other purposes and according to different legal bases of processing.  We use information collected to primarily provide solutions and services, to respond to requests about our solutions and services, to protect our rights and the rights of others, to provide you with personalized digital advertising and marketing, to provide customer service, to detect, prevent, mitigate and investigate fraudulent or illegal activities, and to communicate with you about your account and our solutions and services.  See the table below to learn more about examples of our processing purposes.
4.1 What we process information for
Description of processing purpose
Legal Basis
Categories of Information Processed
Categories of Recipients
To prepare a contract with you or your business entity for products and services for execution and send it to you for execution
Entry into or performance of a contract
Account Registration Data
Payment Data
Shipping and Logistics Data
External technical service providers
External professional service providers
Ritchie Bros. corporate family members
To publish and promote your assets, listings and related content on the websites, marketplaces or in the applications of Ritchie Bros. multi-channel solutions or of cooperating third party publishers and advertisers
Entry into or performance of a contract
Transaction Data
Shipping and Logistics Data
External technical service providers
Ritchie Bros. corporate family members
External operators of websites, applications, services and tools
To register you to bid in-person at a live auction event and assign you a bidding number; approve and monitor bidding limits or privileges on our transactional solutions (including on GovPlanet after conducting a check in the US Federal System for Award Management); and process bidding deposits or authorizations where required after performing identity and address verification and credit card checks
Entry into or performance of a contract
Legitimate Interests
Account Registration Data
Payment Data
Online Account Usage Data
External technical service providers
Ritchie Bros. corporate family members
External operators of websites, applications, services and tools
To create an online account for you permitting you, and others added to your account, to access our websites, applications and other tools across the various Ritchie Bros. solutions, including the online bidding platform and mobile apps
Entry into or performance of a contract
Account Registration Data
Payment Data
External technical service providers
Ritchie Bros. corporate family members
To enable and perform online and offline auction transactions with us, including processing motor vehicle titles or transfers of equipment requiring entry in national registries more efficiently, collecting and paying fees or money owed (including proving chain of ownership of assets to a buyer's lender in order to facilitate the lender's financing of the auction sale), processing payments (including processing tax exemptions and refunds), and connecting IronPlanet marketplace sellers and buyers to facilitate the pick-up and release of items (including in cases of terminated, failed or subsequently voided transactions), or to connect Mascus marketplace advertisers and interested buyers to facilitate a possible transaction
Entry into or performance of a contract
Legitimate Interests
Otherwise Permitted by Law
Account Registration Data
Transaction Data
Payment Data
Shipping and Logistics Data
Online Account Usage Data
External technical service providers
Ritchie Bros. corporate family members
Buyers and sellers on IronPlanet marketplaces
Advertisers on the Mascus marketplace
To provide auction-related and value-added services, including completing appraisals or inspections, arranging for transportation and insurance of your assets or extended warranties, assisting with export and import of assets, storing of your assets, facilitating repair and refurbishment of assets with our service providers
Entry into or performance of a contract
Account Registration Data
Transaction Data
Shipping and Logistics Data
External technical service providers
Ritchie Bros. corporate family members
External operators of websites, applications, services and tools
To enable you to use certain services (ours or a cooperating third party) or make available functionality of our websites applications and tools where you request them, including processing geolocation data to provide you with location-based search results when using mobile apps
Consent
Entry into or performance of a contract
Account Registration Data
Transaction Data
Shipping and Logistics Data
Online Account Usage Data
Geolocation Data
External technical service providers
Ritchie Bros. corporate family members
External operators of websites, applications, services and tools
To conduct credit checks by pulling credit reports and other credit information to assess creditworthiness and facilitate credit approvals or the leasing or financing of assets with our lending partners
Consent
Application and Identity Data
Credit and Financial Data
Transaction Data
Third party operators of websites, applications, services and tools we cooperate with
Lending and financial product partners whom we work with to provide financing and leasing products and services
To communicate with you, either directly or through a cooperating third party, about:
account issues and warnings – e.g. dispute resolution, other customer service items, data privacy requests, cybersecurity events
service functionality – e.g. outages, saved searches, watchlist items, missed buyer inquires on Mascus and ad alerts
transactions – e.g. consignments, listings, sales, purchases, recall notices from Original Equipment Manufacturers (OEMs) and dealers
marketing collateral – e.g. emails from members of the Ritchie Bros. group about sales events, equipment, events and other offers from Ritchie Bros. multiple solutions
research – e.g. opinion polls or surveys
promotions – e.g. phone calls about available equipment or other items for sale, or to offer financing or leasing products and services offered by Ritchie Bros. Financial Services or other financing service providers
via emails, phone calls, mail, notifications, or other messages (e.g. SMS or WhatsApp), consistent with any permissions you have communicated to us where applicable
Entry into or performance of a contract
Legitimate Interest
Consent
Otherwise Permitted by Law
Account Registration Data
Referred Lead Data
Auction Lead Data
Transaction Data
Online Account Usage Data
Customer Service Data
Industry Preference, Interest and Feedback Data
External technical service providers
Ritchie Bros. corporate family members
External operators of websites, applications, services and tools
OEMs and their dealers
To conduct research and surveys, gather feedback, facilitate your participation in contests and sweepstakes, create marketing collateral using your image or testimonial
Legitimate Interest
Consent
Account Registration Data
Industry Preference, Interest and Feedback Data
Online Activity Data
Data for research and surveys is aggregated and de-identified for further use after collection
External technical service providers
Ritchie Bros. corporate family members
To protect our rights, reputation, safety and property, or that of third parties, including:
by recording and analyzing CCTV footage of our physical offices and auction sites, and
tracking details of attendees and others visiting our auction sites (e.g. to inspect or transport assets)
Entry into or performance of a contract
Legitimate Interest
Account Registration Data
Transaction Data
Customer Service Data
Visitor and Incident Log Data
CCTV Data
Law enforcement agencies, courts, government authorities or agencies, public bodies
External professional service providers
Ritchie Bros. corporate family members
To participate in proceedings conducted by courts, public agencies or authorities, law enforcement, or other public bodies if there is a legal obligation to this effect or we legitimately consider disclosure of information is necessary to mitigate or prosecute illegal activity
Comply with Law
Legitimate Interests
Otherwise Permitted by Law
All categories
Law enforcement agencies, courts, government authorities or agencies, public bodies
External professional service providers
Ritchie Bros. corporate family members
Third parties that are part of legal proceedings
To prevent, detect, mitigate, investigate and take action against fraud, security breaches and other prohibited or unlawful activities (e.g. money laundering and terrorist financing), or the violation of our contacts and other policies, including the assessment of corresponding risks, by for example:
the use of captchas or telephone number verification)
monitoring account activity
conducting screening of global sanctions lists to prevent the trade of equipment or other items with embargoed countries, designated persons or entities
reviewing bill of lading and other documentation to ensure buyers of assets through our transactional solutions are not transporting assets to embargoed countries
Comply with Law
Legitimate Interests
Otherwise Permitted by Law
Account Registration Data
Application and Identity Data
Transaction Data
Payment Data
Shipping and Logistics Data
Online Account Usage Data
Device Connection Data
Law enforcement agencies, courts, government authorities or agencies, public bodies
External technical and professional service providers
Ritchie Bros. corporate family members
Third parties that are part of legal proceedings
To comply with subpoenas, warrants or other legal processes or to cooperate with government or public authorities' or agencies' inspections or investigations, or protect the interests of a third party involved in legal disputes if we legitimately consider disclosure of information is necessary to avert severe disadvantages
Comply with Law
Legitimate Interests
Otherwise Permitted by Law
All categories
Law enforcement agencies, courts, government authorities or agencies, public bodies
External professional service providers
Ritchie Bros. corporate family members
Third parties that are part of legal proceedings
To monitor and improve the information security of systems, applications and tools
Comply with Law
Legitimate Interests
Otherwise Permitted by Law
Online Account Usage Data
Geolocation Data
Device Connection Data
External professional service providers
Ritchie Bros. corporate family members
To keep complete and accurate financial records of our transactions and trade registers as required by applicable law
Comply with Law
Account Registration Data
Transaction Data
Payment Data
External professional service providers
Ritchie Bros. corporate family members
To record customer service calls for internal training and dispute resolution
Legitimate Interests
Otherwise Permitted by Law
Customer Service Data
External technical service providers
Ritchie Bros. corporate family members
To analyze and troubleshoot errors, crashes or bugs that relate to our systems and applications to remedy issues or to make our user experience better, or to test our use of new services, applications or tools
Legitimate Interests
Otherwise Permitted by Law
Online Account Usage Data
Device Connection Data
External technical service providers
Ritchie Bros. corporate family members
To personalize, measure the quality and success of, deliver and improve our emails, digital advertisements and content in the online offerings of members of the Ritchie Bros. group of companies or those of third parties across the web, including:
contextual personalization based on user interactions with our online offerings or after considering other information we have about a user
tracking calls placed to us for products and services and combine with the user's other interactions with our websites or webforms
combining and analyzing insight reports using data about user transaction history, patterns of usage of our websites or after combining user information with data relating to your use of services we provide (e.g. to understand the secondary equipment market and develop new products, services or features)
tracking usage of Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers' or IronPlanet's websites (such as creation of equipment watchlists or saved searches) and interaction with Ritchie Bros. Financial Services' email communications or online credit applications
Legitimate Interests
Otherwise Permitted by Law
Transaction Data
Online Account Usage Data
Device Connection Data
Online Activity Data
External technical service providers
Ritchie Bros. corporate family members
To track whether a call is placed to a seller advertising assets for sale on the Mascus marketplace to analyze buyer activity and combine with the user's other internet activity on the marketplace to generate buyer insight reports and assess the effectiveness of seller advertising
Legitimate Interests
Otherwise Permitted by Law
Online Account Usage Data
Device Connection Data
Online Activity Data
External technical service providers
Mascus seller advertisers
To facilitate sellers' compliance with legal obligations, including:
supplying to California sellers a list of buyers for their assets to facilitate compliance with California Air Resources Board record keeping requirements
sharing with government or public agency sellers lists of bidders for their assets to facilitate compliance with federal, state or municipal bylaws, rules or policies
Legitimate Interests
Otherwise Permitted by Law
Account Registration Data
Transaction Data
Auction sellers
Government authorities or agencies, and public bodies
To facilitate OEMs and their dealers understanding the secondary market for their equipment and their communication with bidders and buyers at Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers and IronPlanet sales events about warranties, parts and other products and services.
Legitimate Interests
Otherwise Permitted by Law
Account Registration Data
Transaction Data
OEMs and their dealers
To analyze and generate leads and prospects for financing and other services for Ritchie Bros. Financial Services
Legitimate Interests
Otherwise Permitted by Law
Account Registration Data
Auction Lead Data
Online Account Usage Data
Online Activity Data
External technical service providers
Ritchie Bros. Financial Services
To enhance, categorize and prioritize financing leads, prospects and applicants and score them based on predicted readiness to bid or buy, type of borrower and creditworthiness (including by sharing limited non-personal information with external service providers specializing in aggregating business credit data and supplying business credit reports)
Legitimate Interests
Otherwise Permitted by Law
Account Registration Data
Loan Approval Data
Online Account Usage Data
Online Activity Data
Credit and Financial Data
Referred Lead Data
Auction Lead Data
External technical service providers
To comply with audit obligations under our contractual arrangements with financing referral providers
Legitimate Interests
Otherwise Permitted by Law
Referred Lead Data
Loan Approval Data
External operators of websites, applications, services and tools whom we have a referral arrangement
To initiate, prepare for and execute a business change, e.g. in the event of a merger with another company, sale of assets, joint venture, reorganization, bankruptcy or takeover by another company, including to negotiate and permit due diligence of the transaction and to plan for and execute integration activities
Legitimate Interests
Otherwise Permitted by Law
All categories
Other entities in the context of a business change
4.2 Data sharing with OEMs and their dealers
As noted above, if you make a bid during a Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers or an IronPlanet sales event, we may share your bid and contact information with the OEM of the lot you bid on and any of the OEM's dealers or representatives in your geographic area, if the OEM or dealer/representative entered into a contractual arrangement with us.  We do not trade this information in exchange for money.  OEMs and their dealers or representatives use this information to pursue their legitimate interest of understanding the lifecycle of their equipment and the secondary market for their equipment, to communicate with you about their products and services, and for other purposes disclosed in their privacy policies. Once disclosed, this information will be governed by the OEM's or the OEM dealer's privacy policy and will be subject to the laws of the jurisdiction in which the OEM or OEM dealer processes the information. See "Privacy related requests and your preferences" below on how to opt-out of this sharing and how to request which OEMs and dealers your information was disclosed to during the 12-month period preceding the date of your request.  For more information, visit our "Data Handling and Sharing FAQ".
4.3 Data usage between Ritchie Bros. corporate family members
In pursuit of our common interests we permit access to personal information among members of the Ritchie Bros. corporate family for purposes consistent with this Privacy Statement. Where permitted by law, you may receive promotional and other communications from these related family members.  See our "Data Handling and Sharing FAQ" for more information.  To the extent that Ritchie Bros. corporate family members have access to your personal information, they will follow practices that are at least as restrictive as the practices described in this Privacy Statement.
4.4 Automated decision-making
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers and IronPlanet use automated decision-making technologies to assist in determining a user's bidding privileges and whether a deposit is required prior to bidding.  This processing assists us in protecting our interests and the integrity of our auctions and efficiently make decisions to extend to you the contractual right to bid at an auction.  Our decision on bidding privileges or a deposit may be reviewed by a Customer Care agent.
5. International transfer
Data we collect is transferred to database servers located in various regions, including Canada, European member states, Serbia and the United States. In addition, our personnel and our third-party service providers whom we transfer your information to for our business purposes may also store and access (and in the case of service providers, onward transfer to) your personal information in other countries. These countries may offer a different level of data protection and may have different data protection rules than your country of residence. In certain circumstances courts, law enforcement agencies, regulatory agencies or security authorities in those other foreign jurisdictions may be entitled to access your information.
Under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and other data protection laws, information about individuals who are entitled to protection under those laws may only be transferred from their region to other regions if certain requirements are met.  When we transfer your personal information from outside the EEA or UK, we rely on a variety of measures to support the transfer under EU or UK law, as applicable. As the European Commission and UK government consider Canada to be a country which provides adequate data protection, information may be transferred from the EEA or UK to Canada.  In other cases, we may rely on a service provider's registration in the EU-US Privacy Shield and Swiss-US Privacy Shield (if sent to the US) and/or contractual means to require administrative and technological safeguards designed to mitigate the threat of unauthorized access, use or disclosure of your information (such as standard data protection clauses issued or approved by the European Commission (2010/87/EU, 2001/497/EC or 2004/915/EC).  Please contact us if you have any questions about the transmission of information among members of the Ritchie Bros. corporate family or our transfers to service providers.
6. Storage and erasure
We and our service providers store personal information in accordance with applicable data protection laws to the extent necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Statement or for which you are otherwise notified.  We will destroy or obfuscate data in accordance with our data retention and deletion policy unless we are obliged to keep your personal data longer (i.e. for legal or audit purposes).  In general, Ritchie Bros.' retention periods are 7 years.  Permanent deletion of data can be difficult due to the impact on applications and systems.  Where legally permissible, we may restrict further access or usage of data instead of deleting it.
Retention periods vary by region, the service or product in question and applicable law.  We consider the following factors:
Is the information necessary to provide the service or product?  This covers things such as entering into a contract with you, performing the service requested or paid for, or maintaining appropriate business and financial records.
Is the information sensitive in nature?
What statutory, contractual or similar obligations exist?  This covers things such as retaining information as a result of contractual obligations or due to anticipated or pending legal disputes.  Certain laws also stipulate required retention periods for certain information.
What will the impact on the integrity of systems and applications be if the information is removed?
7. Data security
While we take reasonable administrative, technical and physical measures to protect the information you submit or that we collect online and offline against loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure, or modification, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. No Internet, email or mobile application transmission is ever fully secure or error free, nor are firewalls and physical access restrictions impenetrable.
If you believe your account has been abused, please contact us at customercare@ritchiebros.com.
8. Privacy related requests and your preferences
You may request to exercise the data subject rights described in this part by using our dedicated privacy contact form.  If you prefer, you can send correspondence to Ritchie Bros., Attn: Data Privacy Office, 9500 Glenlyon Parkway, Burnaby, British Columbia, Canada, V5J0C6, or call our Customer Service group.
California Residents.  If you are a resident of California, see our State Privacy Disclosures page for specific information on Your California Privacy Rights.
Access to Information.  In some jurisdictions, applicable law provides the right to be informed of and request access to the personal information we hold and process about you.  For instance, for individuals with rights under the GDPR, you may request information on the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal information concerned, the categories of recipients to whom the personal information have been or will be disclosed, the envisaged period for which the personal information will be stored, the existence of the right to request rectification or erasure of personal information or restriction of processing of personal information or to object to such processing, the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, any available information as to the personal information's source (where not collected from you), the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling and, where appropriate, meaningful information on its details.  Access to information may be subject to certain exemptions.
Rectification of Inaccurate or Incomplete Data.  You have the right to ask us to correct inaccurate or incomplete personal information concerning you.  For certain services, you may also use your online account profile page to review and edit some of your personal information.
Data Portability.  For individuals with rights under the GDPR, you may request personal information about you, that you provided to us, be delivered to you in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format and/or request us to transmit this information to another service provider (where technically feasible).
Erasure.  You can request that we erase your personal information and deactivate your applicable user account.  Please note that exemptions and restrictions may apply depending on applicable law.  In some cases, we will not erase the data, but instead restrict further processing (e.g. where the information is still necessary in relation to the purpose for which it was collected or is needed to establish, exercise or defend a legal claim).  We may also obfuscate/pseudonymize or aggregate data where permitted.
Withdrawing Consent.  Where you have provided your consent to our processing of your personal information you may withdraw your consent at any time.  Please specify if the request is a general withdrawal or which specific consent you want to withdraw. Please note that the withdrawal of your consent does not affect the lawfulness of any processing activities based on such consent before its withdrawal.
Restricting Processing. In some jurisdictions, applicable law may give you the right to restrict the ways in which we use your personal information. For instance, under the GDPR, where:
you contest the accuracy of your personal information;
the processing is unlawful but you oppose the erasure of your personal information;
we no longer need your personal information for the purposes of the processing, but you require the information for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; or
you have objected to the processing based on the grounds described in the next paragraph below and pending the verification whether we have legitimate grounds which override your own.
Objecting to Processing.  The GDPR entitles individuals to object to our processing their personal information for certain specific purposes (including profiling) where such processing is based on our legitimate interest. If an individual entitled to do so objects to such processing we will no longer process their personal information for these purposes unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for such processing or such processing is required for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.
If personal information is processed by us for direct marketing purposes, individuals have the right to object at any time to the processing of their personal information for such marketing, which includes profiling to the extent that it is related to such direct marketing.
Lodging Complaints. You have the right to lodge complaints about the personal information processing activities we carry out before competent supervisory authorities. We hope though that if you reach out to us first, we can resolve your complaint amicably.  If not, then refer to the chart below under "Data Controllers" to see which supervisory authority to contact.
Email Communications. We use your email address to communicate with you in order to fulfill any contractual obligations with you (e.g. to send you invoices or settlement statements) and to notify you about important account information (e.g. updates to our terms of use or security notices).  These communications are mandatory.  Where permitted by applicable law, we may send you relevant marketing communications if you have registered and created a account through one of our websites (including rbauction.com, ironplanet.com, truckplanet.com, or govplanet.com) and agreed to our terms of use for your account. We may also send you marketing communications if you have contracted to sell with us or registered to bid in person at any of our live sales events and agreed to our terms at the time of registration. In certain jurisdictions, by doing so, you infer or imply your consent. If you reside in a country that requires that we obtain your express consent, we will ask for you to expressly opt-into communications. Marketing communications may come from the Ritchie Bros. entity that you contracted with when registering an account or registering to sell or bid, or from another member of the Ritchie Bros. corporate family that provides products or services that we think may be of interest to you. If you are receiving marketing emails, you can unsubscribe from these marketing emails by clicking the unsubscribe link in any marketing email you receive.
Data sharing with OEMs and their dealers. We provide you with the right to know what identifiable information and which OEMs and dealers and representatives we have disclosed information to for their use during the 12-month period preceding the date of your request.  Depending on where you live, you may have the right to request data for a greater period of time. To obtain a list of these OEMs, OEM dealers or representatives who we have disclosed your identifiable information to and/or to stop any further disclosure, use the privacy contact form or other options noted above at the beginning of this section.
9. Cookies & similar technologies and your preferences
When you interact with our online offerings and digital content (e.g. emails or banner ads) or mobile apps, we, our service providers and selected third parties may use cookies and similar technologies (e.g. web beacons and mobile identifiers) to make our offerings, content and apps better, faster and safer, to personalize our advertising across the web, or to provide users a personalized experience.
Cookies are small text files that are automatically created by your browser and stored on your device when triggered by the online offering or mobile app.  Web beacons operate in conjunction with cookies as a small imperceptible graphic image that tracks a user action when taken (e.g. clicking on a link in an email).
Our use of these technologies falls into four categories:
Category
Description
Operationally necessary
Enable users to navigate and use functionality of the online offering or mobile app
Functionality related
Improve a user's experience by enabling personalization functionality on the website. Also allows us to analyze and optimize the operation of the offering (e.g. monitoring load times) or track user interaction to understand usage patterns (e.g. clicks, page views)
Advertising or targeting related
Understand your interests and behavior online and make the ad content you see on the web, in email or on social networks more relevant to you
Some of these technologies may be permanently placed on your device until you remove them (persistent cookies) while others are temporary and are removed after you close your browser (session cookies).
Our service providers use of your data on our behalf is subject to contractual arrangements between us and them.  When you take certain actions, or engage with advertisements of our services, on other websites across the internet, selected third-party organizations place and use cookies and similar technologies to collect data about your activities.  This data may be combined with other data they have acquired and used to profile your interests and serve you advertisements of interest.  The processing of your data by these third parties is subject to their privacy practices over which we have no control.
You may click the button below to access Ritchie Bros.' Cookie Consent Manager. It is a browser cookie-based tool that may allow you to modify settings related to certain Functional or Advertising cookies and related technologies. It is not possible to modify settings to operationally Required cookies and related technologies. The tool works by communicating the selected setting to third party companies to initiate a third party's opt-in/opt-out mechanism, if available. The effect of such selection may be described in the third party's cookie and/or privacy statements. If the tool is unable to integrate with a third party this will be noted in the Detailed Settings description within the tool with information about such third party. The Detailed Settings descriptions will also provide information about cookies used on our online offering.
The tool will only work on the Internet browser you use to make your choice and it will only function properly if your browser is set to accept third-party browser cookies. If you delete cookies, change browsers, computers or operating systems, you will need to make a new selection.
You are always free to completely block cookies if your browser or device permits, although doing so will interfere with your use of some of our websites' features or content.  Review your browser settings to do so.
For more information about targeting and advertising cookies and how you can opt-out from a range of third parties generally, visit:
Network Advertising Initiative: http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices
U.S. Digital Advertising Alliance: http://www.aboutads.info/choices
Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada: http://youradchoices.ca
European Digital Advertising Alliance: http://www.youronlinechoices.eu
Note that using the opt-out tools provided by these initiatives are also browser and device specific. As well, deleting cookies can remove your opt-out preferences, so you will need to periodically refresh your opt-out preferences.
To set "Limit Ad Tracking" on various iOS devices, please click here.
To opt-out of Google interest-based ads on Android, open your Google Settings app > Ads > Enable "Opt out of interest-based advertising"
Certain of our service providers allow you to directly limit their ability to target you with advertising.  Follow their respective instructions below.  Please note this list is subject to change.  Contact us as noted at the beginning of this Privacy Statement for the most up-to-date listing.
Provider
Details
Google Ads
Optout by updating your Google Ad Settings. There you will also find instructions to permanently opt-out through the use of an installed browser plug-in.
Microsoft Ads (Bing Ads)
Optout by updating your Microsoft Ad Settings.
Facebook Ads (including Custom Audiences)
You may adjust your settings by visiting Facebook's ad preferences page, logging-in and adjusting your settings.
LinkedIn Ads (including Matched Audiences)
You may adjust your settings by visiting LinkedIn's ad settings page, logging-in and adjusting your settings.
Criteo
For more information about Criteo's privacy practices generally or to opt-out of further data collection by Criteo, please click here.
Vizury
For more information about Vizury's privacy practices generally or to opt-out of further data collection by Vizury, please click here.
Hotjar
For more information about Hotjar's privacy practices generally or to opt-out of further data collection by Hotjar, please click here.
10. Data Controllers
The Ritchie Bros. company responsible for the handling of your personal information depends on the brand you are interacting with and where you are located:
A. Core asset disposition services
Brand
Location
Ritchie Bros. controller
Notice Address
Lead Supervisory Authority (where applicable)
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
Inside the EEA and the United Kingdom
Joint Controllers: Ritchie Bros. Shared Services B.V.
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers (Canada) Ltd.
Except for RB Logistics services, which are provided by: Ritchie Bros. B.V.
Bijster 3, 4817 HX, Breda, The Netherlands
Dutch Data Protection Authority
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
Inside the EEA and the United Kingdom
Designated EEA Representative: Ritchie Bros. Shared Services B.V.
Bijster 3, 4817 HX, Breda, The Netherlands
Dutch Data Protection Authority
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
Inside the EEA and the United Kingdom
Designated UK Representative: Ritchie Bros. UK Limited
One Fleet Place, London England EC4M 7WS
Information Commissioner's Office
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers
Any other region not otherwise specified
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers (Canada) Ltd.
9500 Glenlyon Parkway, Burnaby, BC V5J 0C6
IronPlanet
Inside the EEA and the United Kingdom
Joint Controllers: IronPlanet Limited
Ritchie Bros. Shared Services B.V.
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers (Canada) Ltd.
Bijster 3, 4817 HX, Breda, The Netherlands
Dutch Data Protection Authority
IronPlanet
Inside the EEA and the United Kingdom
Designated EEA Representative: Ritchie Bros. Shared Services B.V.
Bijster 3, 4817 HX, Breda, The Netherlands
Dutch Data Protection Authority
IronPlanet
Inside the EEA and the United Kingdom
Designated UK Representative: Ritchie Bros. UK Limited
One Fleet Place, London England EC4M 7WS
Information Commissioner's Office
IronPlanet
Any other region not otherwise specified
Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers (Canada) Ltd.
9500 Glenlyon Parkway, Burnaby, BC V5J 0C6
Mascus
Any region
Mascus International B.V.
Bijster 3, 4817 HX, Breda, The Netherlands
Dutch Data Protection Authority
Mascus
Any region
Designated UK Representative: Ritchie Bros. UK Limited
One Fleet Place, London England EC4M 7WS
Information Commissioner's Office
Leake
Any region Note: Leake Auction hosts auctions only in the United States
Leake Auction Company
4000 Pine Lake Road, Lincoln, NE USA 68516
B. Other asset disposition-related services
Brand
Location
Ritchie Bros. controller
Notice Address
Lead Supervisory Authority (where applicable)
Ritchie Bros. Financial Services
Any region Note: RBFS services are only available in to the following regions:  Canada, United States, Australia, Mexico
Ritchie Bros. Financial Services Ltd.
9500 Glenlyon Parkway, Burnaby, BC V5J 0C6
Ritchie Bros. Asset Solutions
Any region
Mascus International B.V.
Bijster 3, 4817 HX, Breda, The Netherlands
Dutch Data Protection Authority
11. Other information regarding privacy
11.1 Responsibilities for receipt of information through services
When using our solutions, you may receive or have access to another person's information.  For example:
While we do not identify sellers and buyers on the IronPlanet marketplaces, certain sellers may offer inspection privileges in which case bidders will have access to name, address and contact information of an equipment manager to arrange for inspection
Once a buyer pays for items on the IronPlanet marketplace, they will receive information about the seller (name, address, contact information) to facilitate the pick-up of their purchases
Sellers advertising on the public Mascus marketplace receive the contact information of interested buyers when an inquiry is made through the contact functionality
Interested buyers have access to the name and contact information of a seller advertising an item in a listing on the public Mascus marketplace
You may use the information received or which you've been given access only to interact with the other person as part of your transaction or to comply with regulatory obligations.  You must comply with all applicable law and, in particular, provide the other person with any data subject rights to which they are entitled.  You are solely responsible for determining whether you may lawfully use the information received or accessed for other purposes.  Note that certain information may also be subject to usage restrictions in accordance with our terms of use or buyer terms and conditions.
11.2 Providing us with third party personal information
If you provide us with personal information relating to another person, you must obtain the consent of the person or the disclosure of the information to us must be otherwise legally permissible. You must inform the other person of how we process personal data in accordance with this Privacy Statement.
11.3 Children's privacy
Our solutions are not intended for use by children.  We do not knowingly collect information from users or participants who are considered children under applicable laws.  To participate in an auction or use our services, you must be 18 or older.
11.4 Logging in to IronPlanet's online marketplaces using your Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers web account
We permit you to use your Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers online web account credentials to log in to IronPlanet's online marketplaces.  To facilitate this cross-solution authentication, when you register an account with Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers, we automatically create a dormant account for you on IronPlanet that becomes active only when you first sign-in.
11.5 Logging in to a preferred provider's site using Ritchie Bros. credentials
We permit certain of our preferred partners to authenticate your online access to their website or webservices using your IronPlanet or Ritchie Bros. Auctioneers online credentials.  If you choose to do so, when logging-in you will be redirected to our website to enter your credentials.  Once you successfully login, you will be redirected again back to the partner's site. Your personal information collected by the partner when using their site will be handled by them for the purposes they disclose to you (such as in their privacy notices).
11.6 Links and Social Media Presences
Our websites contain links to other sites including sites maintained by our customers, third party service providers or preferred or recommended providers. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to read the privacy notices of all websites they choose to visit that collect personal information.
Ritchie Bros. maintains publicly accessible profiles in various social networks listed below. Our social media presence ensures an internet presence that is as comprehensive as possible – which supports our legitimate commercial and marketing interests.
Social networks are able to analyze your user behaviour when you visit their websites or other sites with integrated social media plug-ins, or you use their mobile apps.  When you're logged-in to your social media account and you visit our social media presence, or you click on a hyperlink to our social media presence and then log-in to your account, the social media operator associates your visit with your social media user account.  It may also be possible for the operator to identify you when you are not logged-in or do not have an account.  All of this is made possible by the placement of tracking tools on your browser or device that are associated with the social media operator.  These allow the operator to receive information from our websites which it combines with information it receives elsewhere on the internet or from other sources.
Social media operators use the information gathered about you to create user profiles that store your preferences and interests.  The profiles are used to tailor advertising to you based on your interests both within and outside of their respective social media sites and across any device you've used to access the social media site.  The information is also used by operators to provide anonymous measurement statistics and demographic data to us as administrators of our social media presence.  We use this data to create content more relevant to our target audiences.  For details of other uses of this data by operators, please refer to their respective privacy notices. For further information about our collection of data using cookies, web beacons and similar tools when you interact with our digital services, check out "Cookies & similar technologies and your preferences".
For individuals with rights under the GDPR, when you visit one our social media presences, we are jointly responsible as controllers together with the social media operator for the data processing activities triggered by your visit.  You may assert your rights against either of us, but please note, despite having joint responsibility we have no real influence over the data processing activities conducted by the social media operator.  Refer to the information below for the specifics of each social media operator.
Social Media Presence
Provider
Important Info.
Facebook Fanpages
Facebook Ireland Limited 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2 Ireland
The following agreement governs our joint responsibility for processing: https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/ page_controller_addendum
You can set your advertising preferences vi your user account.  Click below and login: https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads For further details please refer to the Facebook privacy policy: https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/
Instagram Profile
Instagram Inc. 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA, 94025, USA
For details on the processing of your information by Instagram, review to its privacy policy: https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388
Twitter Pages
Twitter International Company One Cumberland Place, Fenian Street Dublin 2, D02 AX07 Ireland
You may adjust your Twitter data privacy settings independently via your user account. To do so, click on this link and log in: https://twitter.com/personalization
For further details please refer to the Twitter privacy policy: https://twitter.com/privacy
YouTube Channels
YouTube LLC 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, USA
You can set your advertising preferences independently via your user account. To do so, click on this link and log in: https://myaccount.google.com/intro/data-and-personalization For further details please refer to the YouTube privacy policy: https://policies.google.com/privacy
LinkedIn Profile
LinkedIn Ireland Unlimited Company
The following agreement governs our joint responsibility for processing: https://legal.linkedin.com/pages-joint-controller-addendum
If you would like to deactivate LinkedIn advertising cookies, please use the following link: https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out For details of how your personal data are processed, please refer to the LinkedIn privacy policy: https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy
11.7 Regional disclosures
This Privacy Statement establishes our global principles for the collection, use, disclosure and storage of personal information that is processed by Ritchie Bros. member companies in the course of our operations.  Certain places where you are doing business with us or where the website or application you are interacting with is located or hosted may have specific requirements concerning personal information which may be found under our State Privacy Disclosures.
Node: dc1vplfry05.rbauction.net
Node : dc1vplfry05.rbauction.net Build : 514 Revision : 112420200854
This field {0} is required. {0} is invalid. {0} can only contain letters [a-z]. {0} can only contain letters and numbers. {0} must be a number. {0} can only contain numbers [0-9]. {0} must be a valid password. {0} must be a valid email address. {0} must be a valid URL. {0} must be a valid date of the format YYYY-MM-DD. {0} must be at least {1} characters. {0} must be no more than {1} characters. {0} must be between {1} and {2} characters. {0} must be greater than {1}. {0} must be less than {1}. {0} must be between {1} and {2}. {0} and {1} must match. {0} must be a valid postal code. {0} must be a valid zip code. {0} can only contain letters, numbers, dash (-) and dot (.) {0} must be must be greater than 2 characters or be entered as "GD". {0} is an invalid phone number format. Examples of valid formats would be 000-0000 or 0000000.
